Let's focus on the actions that we do to prepare food or to cook food.
让我们专注于我们为准备食物或烹饪食物所做的行动。
One interesting thing to keep in mind when we're preparing food is that whatever action or verb that
当我们准备食物时要记住的一件有趣的事情是，无论是什么动作或动词，
we do to a particular food then changes the name of that thing.
我们对一种特定的食物做了然后改变了那个东西的名字。
So all we do then is use the verb to say what we did to the food or the ingredient.
所以我们所做的就是用动词来说明我们对食物或成分做了什么。
That's the particular thing that's going to be in it like carrots or whatever.
这就是其中的特殊事物，例如胡萝卜或其他东西。
And then we add E.D. to that and it becomes an adjective becomes an adjective for that thing.
然后我们添加 E.D.到那个，它变成一个形容词变成那个东西的形容词。
And that's the new name.
这就是新名字。
OK.
好的。
So let's start with cutting how we cut things.
因此，让我们从切割我们如何切割事物开始。
Well you can just cut things that's a very general word but there are four common words that are used
好吧，你可以删掉一个非常笼统的词，但是有四个常用词
to describe cutting different things there's chop slice dice and cube.
描述切割不同的东西有切碎的骰子和立方体。
What are the differences between these these words.
这些词之间有什么区别。
OK.
好的。
So chop is generally when we don't really care about the size of whatever it is that we're cutting but
所以剁通常是当我们并不真正关心我们正在切割的任何东西的大小时
it's not usually long and thin it's usually irregular and we're usually just doing this action on maybe
它通常不是又长又薄 它通常是不规则的，我们通常只是在做这个动作
a cutting board.
一块砧板。
OK.
好的。
So for example if you're making soup and you need a carrot that's cut into many pieces.
例如，如果你正在做汤，你需要一个切成许多块的胡萝卜。
We often call that chopped carrot chopped carrot chopped carrot.
我们常称切碎的胡萝卜切碎的胡萝卜切碎的胡萝卜。
So PPE E.D. that's the action.
所以 PPE E.D.这就是行动。
We're doing this cutting into many pieces.
我们正在把它切成很多块。
Now we have chopped carrot chopped lettuce for example.
现在我们以切碎的胡萝卜切碎的生菜为例。
You could have chopped vegetables of any kind could chop meat whatever it is.
您可以切碎任何种类的蔬菜，也可以切碎肉。
Usually we're not too focused on the exact size and we are not too careful when we're doing it.
通常我们不会太关注确切的尺寸，而且我们在做的时候也不会太小心。
OK.
好的。
Slice is for long thin things.
切片用于长而薄的东西。
Generally speaking you have for example sliced tomato.
一般来说，你有例如切片番茄。
So if you have a sliced tomato you take a tomato and you cut it into long thin pieces.
所以如果你有一个番茄片，你可以拿一个番茄，然后把它切成细长的小块。
That is a sliced tomato.
那是切好的番茄。
So as I mentioned when you do an action then it changes the name.
因此，正如我在您执行操作时提到的那样，它会更改名称。
So put sliced tomatoes at the top or on top of the salad.
所以把切好的西红柿放在沙拉的顶部或顶部。
OK.
好的。
So that becomes E.D. sliced.
所以这就变成了 E.D.切片。
Notice the pronunciation is not done.
注意发音没有完成。
This one is chopped because it's unvoiced.
这个被切碎了，因为它是清音的。
This one is sliced because this is unvoiced.
这个是切片的，因为它是清音的。
You don't use your voice.
你不用你的声音。
So we say we could say sliced cucumbers we could say sliced bread.
所以我们说我们可以说切片黄瓜我们可以说切片面包。
We could say sliced ham whatever we need to say but generally we're focusing on longer thinner things
我们可以说切片火腿，但通常我们专注于更长更薄的东西
rather than cutting things up in an irregular shape which would be chopping.
而不是将东西切成不规则的形状，这将是切碎的。
OK dice.
好的骰子。
Well dicing is very similar to chopping something except the pieces will be smaller.
切丁与切东西非常相似，只是碎片会更小。
We one very small pieces.
我们一小块。
So if we do that to an onion then instead of having a chopped onion maybe the sizes are this big.
因此，如果我们对洋葱这样做，那么可能不是切碎的洋葱，而是这么大。
Now we're going to have diced onion so a chopped onion like that a sliced onion circular pieces generally.
现在我们要切洋葱，所以切碎的洋葱就像切好的洋葱圆片一般。
All right thin.
没事瘦。
And then a diced onion.
然后是一个洋葱丁。
Tiny little pieces of onion that we're going to put into a dish for example.
例如，我们将放入盘子中的小洋葱片。
OK.
好的。
Diced onion again.
再切洋葱。
Psst psst chopped sliced diced the pronunciation of D for all three of these is.
psst psstchopped sliced diced 这三个都是 D 的发音。
But this one will be different.
但这一次会有所不同。
OK.
好的。
Now when you cube something this is a verb cube to cube cube is also a noun.
现在，当您立方体某物时，这是一个动词立方体，立方体立方体也是一个名词。
You cut it into the shape of a cube.
你把它切成立方体的形状。
So for example cubed beef or cubed potato.
例如牛肉块或土豆块。
Notice I'm saying cube.
注意我说的是立方体。
Why am I saying Cube did not cubed like the others.
为什么我说立方体没有立方体像其他人一样。
I said for the others let's because this book uses the voice but if we have a voiced sound then it's
我为其他人说让我们，因为这本书使用语音，但如果我们有语音，那就是
going to be pronounced as.
将被发音为。
So cubed potato and cube beef whatever it is for example for a soup that we're making is the shape generally
所以土豆块和牛肉块无论是什么，例如我们做的汤都是一般的形状
doesn't have to be exactly of a cube which is a 3D 3D square.
不必完全是 3D 3D 正方形的立方体。
So we're maybe a little bit more focused on what the shape is and we care maybe more than if we're chopping
所以我们可能更关注形状是什么，我们可能比我们切菜更关心
something.
某物。
OK.
好的。
So I hope that's pretty simple.
所以我希望这很简单。
Chopped sliced diced cubed all cutting actions.
切碎切丁切丁所有切割动作。
And every time you finish doing it then it is that thing E.D. and then the original ingredient that
每次你完成它时，它就是 E.D.然后是原来的成分
you used cubed beef chopped onion sliced tomato diced cucumber OK.
你用切块的牛肉切洋葱切番茄切丁黄瓜OK。
That's pretty simple.
这很简单。
Now here are some other actions that follow the same rule.
现在这里有一些遵循相同规则的其他操作。
We have mixed peeled and washed six unvoiced.
我们混合了去皮和洗过的六个清音。
So we set mixed peel or voiced so we say peeled and wash.
所以我们设置混合剥离或浊音，所以我们说剥离和洗涤。
Sheesh unvoiced so we say washed.
Sheesh 清音，所以我们说洗过。
OK.
好的。
So for example we could say mixed greens.
例如，我们可以说混合果岭。
That means the vegetables that we're using are all green maybe lettuce maybe spinach for example lettuce
这意味着我们使用的蔬菜都是绿色的，也许是生菜，也许是菠菜，例如生菜
spinach.
菠菜。
OK.
好的。
We have those together.
我们有这些。
That would be mixed greens.
那将是混合蔬菜。
OK.
好的。
And we have peel which means we cut the skin off of something OK.
我们有果皮，这意味着我们可以将皮肤从某些东西上切下来。
We wouldn't use that for example for a banana although the thing on the outside of a banana is a banana
例如，我们不会将它用于香蕉，尽管香蕉外面的东西是香蕉
peel.
剥。
We usually don't say peeled bananas.
我们通常不说去皮的香蕉。
I guess you can but it's not so common.
我想你可以，但它并不常见。
Usually it's when we cut off with a knife the outside or the skin of something for example peeled apples
通常是当我们用刀切掉某物的外部或皮肤时，例如去皮的苹果
or we might say peeled potatoes peeled potatoes.
或者我们可以说去皮土豆去皮土豆。
OK.
好的。
If you have peeled potatoes then you don't have to say peel the potatoes.
如果你有去皮的土豆，那么你不必说去皮土豆。
You could say add peeled potatoes to whatever thing you're making then you don't need to say you need
您可以说将去皮土豆添加到您正在制作的任何东西中，然后您就不需要说您需要
to peel the potatoes because in order to get peeled potatoes you first have to peel them.
去皮土豆，因为为了得到去皮的土豆，你首先必须去皮。
Otherwise they're not peeled.
否则他们不会去皮。
Right.
正确的。
So that can be actually a useful little tool for making a description of what you're cooking easier
所以这实际上是一个有用的小工具，可以更轻松地描述你正在烹饪的东西
and simpler.
更简单。
You don't have to say things twice.
你不必说两遍。
Obviously washed whatever it is you might wash.
显然洗了任何你可能洗的东西。
Hopefully you wash most things like fruit and vegetables before you before you actually eat them.
希望你在真正吃水果和蔬菜之前先把它们洗干净。
For example you could say washed lettuce or whatever it is whatever it is.
例如，您可以说洗过的生菜或任何它是什么。
OK.
好的。
So I hope that's pretty straight forward.
所以我希望这很简单。
Now let's get into the ways that we cook things and these are the common ones and it follows the same
现在让我们来看看我们做饭的方式，这些是常见的，它遵循相同的
rule.
规则。
If you do these actions then that thing then becomes that with E.D. after it as the adjective.
如果你做这些动作，那么那个东西就会变成 E.D.在它之后作为形容词。
So baked potatoes baked potatoes fried potatoes stir fried potatoes.
所以烤土豆烤土豆炒土豆炒土豆。
Yeah.
是的。
Maybe if we're making Chinese food boiled potatoes.
也许如果我们正在做中国菜煮土豆。
Yeah sure steamed potatoes maybe.
是的，当然可能是蒸土豆。
I don't know any steamed potatoes but I guess it's possible grilled potatoes.
我不知道任何蒸土豆，但我想可能是烤土豆。
Why don't we just do a very quick example for each of these.
为什么我们不为每一个做一个非常简单的例子。
So I will bake a potato.
所以我会烤一个土豆。
Now I have baked potatoes and I've done that in an oven.
现在我已经烤了土豆，我已经在烤箱里做了。
I will fry mushrooms.
我会炒蘑菇。
Why not.
为什么不。
Now I have fried mushrooms and then I will fry them in a pan.
现在我有炒蘑菇，然后我会在平底锅里煎。
OK.
好的。
Now stir fry is usually where you have constant motion but it's kind of the same thing.
现在炒菜通常是你不断运动的地方，但它是一样的。
Deep frying is when you put it deep in oil stir frying is often connected with Chinese cuisine.
油炸是将其放入油中翻炒通常与中国菜有关。
So I could have for example I could have stir fried stir fried tomato and eggs and I might do that in
所以我可以有，例如，我可以炒番茄和鸡蛋，我可能会这样做
a walk to special sort of pan which is bigger it's more bowl shaped like boil.
步行到一种特殊的平底锅，它更大，更像是煮沸的碗。
They boiled and we've boiled while these boiled cabbage boring.
他们煮了，我们煮了，而这些煮白菜很无聊。
And we'll do that in a pot.
我们将在一个锅中做到这一点。
Steam has steamed it could have steamed dumplings.
蒸汽已经蒸了它可以蒸饺子。
That's Chinese cuisine and we'll steamed that in a steamer but you could also steam it in a pan I suppose
那是中国菜，我们会用蒸锅蒸，但我想你也可以用平底锅蒸
and then grill say grilled chicken and we would grill it on a hot grill.
然后烧烤说烤鸡，我们会在热烤架上烤。
OK.
好的。
So I hope that's pretty easy.
所以我希望这很容易。
Hope that simple.
希望就这么简单。
Let's now go on and talk about some common cooking phrases that we can use which are related to what
现在让我们继续讨论一些我们可以使用的常见烹饪短语，这些短语与什么有关
we were just describing.
我们只是在描述。